Dr.Tal Ben-Shahar:Hi.Good morning.
大家早上好
So first of all,are there any junior parents today?
首先今天在座的有低年级父母吗
Welcome.Welcome.I'm so glad you are here.
欢迎 欢迎 非常高兴你们能来
I'm even gladder you weren't here on Tuesday.
我更高兴你们周二没有来
So just...just...Just a couple of announcements.
我...要先宣布一点事
Yeah,you know,I was asking myself after Tuesday,
周二之后我一直问自己
"are they ever going to take me seriously again?" I hope so.
"他们以后还会不会认真听我的话了" 我希望如此
Or "will they love me tomorrow?"
或者"他们明天还会喜欢我吗"
So just a couple of announcements.
好了 还是先宣布点事情吧
First,there are many emails regarding the response papers,
首先 我收到很多关于论文的邮件
whether the gratitude letters that you write,
你们写的感谢信
you also need to submit to your,to your TF,
也需要提交给你们的助教
as the response paper.So the answer is yes and no.
作为论文 所以我的回答既不肯定也不否定
Alright,next.Yes! You do need to submit it.
好了 也就是 对 你得提交
However,if the letter is too personal
不过如果那封信过于私人
or you don't feel comfortable for any reason submitting
或者由于任意原因你不太愿意提交
to your TF as well,
给你的助教
just send your TF a note saying "I wrote the letter"
就直接给助教发"我写了那封信"
and we will take your word for it.
我们会信任你的
And...so you don't have to submit it,
所以不是一定要提交
though it would be great if you do.
虽然最好是能提交
The midterm is coming up in a week and a half.
一个半礼拜之后就要期中考
So just a couple of words about the midterm.
所以关于期中考我说几句
What we have decided to do
我们打算期中考
is to just have a multiple choice midterm.
只出选择题
There'll be - can't remember how many - 50? Five zero.
会有... 不太记得了 多少道 50? 50
50 questions on the multiple choice.
50道选择题
And you'll have 75 minutes to do it.
有75分钟的作答时间
So we'll allow for the 10 minutes
这样就可以留出十分钟
or 15 minutes to get organized here.
到十五分钟的时间来组织秩序
It's not going to be a difficult,you know...
考试不会太难
Try to fool you or to catch you.
要愚弄或是考倒你们
It's going to be pretty straight forward.
而是会考得很直接
I've told you my philosophy about exams during the first class,
第一节课我曾告诉过你们我对考试的态度
those of you who remember.
如果你们还记得的话
In the past,I didn't used to have an exam
过去 我不太习惯弄考试
because I remember I wasn't happy taking exams as an undergrad.
因为我记得我本科时就很讨厌考试
And you know do not do unto others.
己所不欲勿施于人嘛
But then,I realize that there was the value to them.
不过后来我意识到考试确实是有价值的
Not a value in terms of differentiation,
不是在于高低分化
grades and stuff,all that.
或者成绩之类的
The value is that the midterm or final gets you to sit down
而在于期中考或期末考可以让你安下心来
and synthesize all the material.
整合所有学过的知识
So if it's a take home,you look for the answers where you are.
如果是家庭作业 你可以找你所需的答案
You take...you just get part of it.
你只掌握了部分的知识
With the midterm or final,
但有期中考或期末考
you sit down and you read everything from lesson 1 to lesson 26.
你就能坐下来从第一课看到最后一课
And then that helps you synthesize
而这可以帮助你整合知识
and hence internalize the material.
进而吸收掌握知识
Because remember what I mentioned time and again:
请记住我反复强调的
this class is built around the spiral theory of knowledge,
这门课是基于螺旋形的知识体系的
meaning everything we talked about in lesson 1,in class 1,
也就是说我们在第一课中讲的内容
is related to class 3,is related to class 7,
与第三课相联系 与第七课相联系
is related to class 24.Everything is interconnected.
与第二十四课有联系 所有东西都是内在相连的
And it's when you sit down,
而只有你静下心来
you know when I talk about the material,I know
当我在讲某个知识时 我知道
it's going to come three weeks from now and I know the connection
接下来的三周我会讲到什么 以及它们的联系
You still don't,but when you sit down and study for the exam,
你们还不能 但当你们坐下来准备考试时
that's when you get to make the connection,
才能建立知识间的联系
and that's when you really internalize the material
才能从更高的层面真正
at a much higher level.So this is why we have it.
吸收掌握知识 所以我们才要举行考试
I know it's not fun however I think it is pedagogically.
我知道这不好玩 但对教学有好处
It is important to sit down and have a run through,
静下心来把知识过一遍是很重要的
whether it's the midterm and again,for the final.
不管是期中考还是期末考
Again,won't be difficult,but do study for it.
再说一次 不会很难 但一定要复习
It would be very straightforward,fact-based.
考试会很直接 基于事实
The midterm,as you can imagine,is not about showing creativity.
可以想象得到 期中考不是要展示创造力
Our goal is that you go over the material and synthesize it.
我们的目标是让你们回顾并掌握知识
If you have any questions,
有任何问题
please email your TFs and they'll be able to answer.
可以给助教发邮件 他们会给予回复
If not,then email me.
如果没有 那就发邮件给我
OK.So where were we last time? Actually can't remember.
好了 上回讲到哪了 其实我不太记得了
I think I repress the whole lesson.
我好像忘了上节课的内容
But I was told that I skipped a few things
不过有人跟我说我跳过了一些东西
so that I could get to the show at the end.
以便最后能完成我的节目
And one thing that I skipped and I want to talk about go back to,
有一样被跳过的东西 我想回头讲一下
after we talked about the body feedback hypothesis.
在我们谈到身体反馈假说之后
You remember the body feedback hypothesis?
还记得身体反馈假说吗
How you shake your hand,how you carry yourself.
你握手的方式 言谈举止
With the facial feedback hypothesis,with your smile,your frown.
还有面部反馈假说 包括微笑 皱眉
That communicates certain message to other people,
这向他人传递了特定的信息
who then reflect back to us and at the same time,
然后他人再反馈回来给我们 与此同时
we are also communicating to ourselves.
我们也在和自己沟通
Am I confident? or am I proud? Or am I afraid and scared?
我自信吗 骄傲吗 或者我害怕恐惧吗
And very often we need to,
很多时候我们需要
as we talk about "fake it till we make it".
正如我所说"不断伪造方能成真"
Because our body,our behavior sends messages to our mind,
因为我们的身体 行为 给我们的思想
to our emotions and affects them.
以及情感提供信息 并影响它们
There was a wonderful research done
有一个很不错的研究
by Haemmerlie and second author,Montgomery.
由Haemmerlie以及第二作者Montgomery完成
Haemmerlie and Montgomery did the following research.
Haemmerlie和Montgomery做了如下研究
They recruited shy heterosexual men.
他们招募了一些内向的直男
Recruited them for the study.Shy,heterosexual men.
招募他们进行研究 内向的性取向正常的男人
And the study was run as follow:
研究是按如下方式进行的
these men were told that the study was about taking certain test
这些人被告知研究就是做一些特定的测试
and they were invited into the equivalent of William James Hall,
他们被邀请到William James大楼
and they were told "unfortunately we were running behind,
然后被告知"很不幸我们进度落后了"
so you have to wait.
"所以你得稍等"
You have to wait until the study actually takes place.
"必须在研究开始之前稍作等待"
In the mean time,you know here is a waiting room
同时等候室在这里
and there are other people waiting for the same test.
有很多人也在等候做相同的测试
And we'll come and get you.
"等到了的时候我们会来叫你"
It may take a while.Sorry.
"可能得等一会 抱歉"
We'll pay you for it for the time you have to wait extra."
"我们会付你额外等待时间的酬劳的"
So they ended up waiting in a waiting room.
于是他就在等候室里等候
And with them was waiting another person.
还有一个人和他一起等
A female,who unbeknownst to them was actually a confederate,
一位女性 他并不知道她其实是共谋者
was actually a part of the study.
是研究的一部分
But they thought she was just like them,waiting,
他以为她和他一样在等候
also waiting in line for the study to take place.
也在等候进行测试
So they were sitting there for 12 minutes with a woman,
于是他和一个女人一起坐了12分钟
whose instruction was to strike up a conversation
那个女人的任务是与这个内向直男
with this shy heterosexual man,and to express a lot of interest
发起对话 并对他所说的东西
and excitement about what they were saying.
表现出极大的兴趣和兴奋感
So they were listening and they were asking questions.
于是他们互相倾听  互相提问
"Wow." "Really?"
"哇" "真的吗"
They were laughing at what they were saying for 12 minutes.
他们在12分钟里谈笑风生
And then,that,
然后
the woman went into the experiment or so they thought.
那女人进去做他们以为的测试
Another woman comes in.Again,for 12 minutes,
另一个女人再进来 又是12分钟
she sits down with the shy heterosexual man
她和这个内向直男坐在一起
and seems very interested and laughs at what he has to say,
表现极大的兴趣 对他说的话发笑
and asks questions.
向他提问
And so on and so...for 12 minutes.
诸如此类 聊12分钟
And the next woman comes in,as she goes into the experiment.
她进去做试验之后 下一个女人又进来
And so on.Six times.
如此类推 一共六次
Six women sitting with the shy heterosexual men,
六个女人坐在这些内向直男身边
being very interested in what they have to say,
对他们所说的话表现极大的兴趣
striking a conversation.72 minutes total.
开启对话 一共72分钟
And then they go into the real experiment,whatever it was.
然后再进行所谓的真正的试验
And then next day,
然后第二天
they are invited for the same experiment again.
他们又被邀请参加同样的试验
And once again,they go through the exact same procedure.
再把完全一样的流程走一遍
For 72 minutes,they sit down with 6 women
72分钟里 他们和六个女人分别坐在一起
who are very interested in what they have to say.
她们对他们的谈话内容表现极大兴趣
And of course,what really the experiment was interested in
当然了 这个试验要研究的就是
was what effect does this have.
这会有什么效果
What effect does this behavior have on their shyness?
这种行为对于他们的内向会有什么效果
And it had radical effects.
而答案是非常大
So over the next 6 months,when they followed upon these,
接下来的半年里 跟踪调查发现
these men suddenly became far less anxious.
这些男人突然变得没那么紧张了
In general,and specifically around women.
总体上来说 尤其是在女人旁边
They became less shy.
他们没有那么害羞了
These men often for the first time in their lives,
这些男人 很多是人生中第一次
initiate relationships and start to date
开始发展感情 开始约会
after 144 minutes of intervention.
在144分钟的干预以后
Radical difference.But there was a problem.
天翻地覆的变化 但有一个问题
What's the problem with many of these psychological experiment?
许多心理学实验的普遍问题是什么
That you have to debrief.
就是必须向受试者报告结果
Exactly.You have to debrief.
没错 你得报告结果
So six months later,the study was over.
因此半年后 试验结束
The researchers invite the men in
研究者重新聚集受试者
and tell them this was just a study.
告诉他们这只是个研究
And these women were actually part of the experiment-
而那些女人其实是试验的一部分
they were told to seem interested.
是被要求表现出兴趣的
Cruel,right? Well,less than they thought.
很残忍对吧 但并不像预想的那样
It made no difference to these men.
这对那些男人没有影响
Because by this time,they were much more outgoing.
因为那时 他们已经外向了许多
They were doing well with the opposite sex.
他们与异性相处愉快
They were going on dates.They were less shy.
他们出去约会 他们不再那么内向
It started a positive spiral.It didn't matter at all.
这开启了一个良性循环 已经完全没关系了
144 minutes changed their lives,
144分钟改变了他们的生活
as far as the dating was concerned at least,if not more.
至少从约会的角度来看
Why? Think back to Bandura's work on self-efficacy.
为什么呢 回忆一下Bandura对自我效能的研究
Nothing breeds success like success.
没有比成功本身对成功更好的催化剂
When they succeeded,they did well,
当他们成功时 做得很好时
they saw themselves doing well- self-perception theory.
他们能看到自己做得很好 --自我知觉理论
Certain conclusions about who they are,
关于对自我的认识和感知
what they are and that led to an upward spiral,
使他们进入良性循环
and continued that upward spiral.
并且保持这个良性循环
Yeah,we talked about 'fake it till we make it',
我们刚刚讲了"不断伪造方能成真"
then watch Marva Collins.
再看看Marva Collins
Chapters of the Fathers.Pirkei Avot.
先祖伦理
One of the seminal Jewish texts:
很重要的犹太教教义写道
"Those whose deeds exceed their wisdom,their wisdom shall endure
"那些行为超越其智慧的人 他们的智慧将恒久"
but those whose wisdom exceeds their deeds,
"但那些智慧超越其行为的人"
their wisdom shall not endure.”
"他们的智慧无法持久"
If we just- remember what I talked about-
如果能记住我说过的
if we just go to a workshop or a class,
当我们参加讨论会或者上课
and understand it on the cognitive level,
并从认知水平上理解它
even have an ah ha moment,a break through,nothing will happen,
即便有灵光乍现的时刻 有突破 也不会发生什么
unless we follow our new found wisdom
除非我们的行为跟上了
or understanding with deeds,with action.Why?
这新闪现的智慧 为什么呢
Because we first make our habits,and then our habits make us.
因为我们首先塑造习惯 然后习惯再反过来塑造我们
And if we are before the workshop or class here,
假设我们在参加学术讨论或上课之前是这个水平
and then our attitude changes but our behavior doesn't,
然后我们的态度改变了 但行为没变
our attitude will be pulled down over time by our habits.
态度会随着时间流逝被习惯又拉回来
So it's only,if we also change our habits over time,
所以只有我们随着时间改变习惯
if we start doing things,if we,for example,
开始做点什么 比如说
put ourselves on the line- cope.
强迫自己做些事 解决些问题
Or if we start doing the gratitude exercise
或者开始做感恩的训练
or writting letters on the regular basis,
或者平时经常写信
or starting physical exercise-
或者开始做运动
arguably being most powerful intervention,
可以证明是最有力的干预
to deal with anxiety,depression as well as the ADHD.
来解决焦虑 沮丧 以及多动症
And that's when we start doing these things
除非我们很快开始做这些事
right after the change is going to be ephemeral
否则这改变就会是短暂的
we are going to go back to where we were before.
我们很快会回到原来的状态
Lasting,permanent change-
持久的长远的改变
attitude change has to be matched by deeds,by behavior.
态度的改变必须要使行为与之匹配
Dan Millman- I mentioned him in class a couple of weeks ago,
Dan Millman 我几周前在课上提过他
The way of peaceful warrior,
在《深夜加油站遇见苏格拉底》一书中
talks about the importance of action and change.
探讨了行动与改变的重要性
He says,quote,"To change the course of your life,
他说 我引述 "要改变人生轨迹
choose one of two basic methods.
就要从两种基本方法中选择
One.You can direct your energy
其一 你可以指引你的能量及
and attention toward trying to fix your mind,find your focus,
注意力 用其整理思想 集中精神
affirm your power,
巩固力量
free your emotions and visualize positive outcomes so that
释放情感以及想象乐观结果
you can finally develop the confidence to display the courage
从而使你最终获得自信 鼓起勇气
to discover the determination to make the commitment
下定决心做出承诺
to feel sufficiently motivated to do what it is you need to do.
获得充分的激励去做你要做的事
Two.Or you can just do it."
其二 你也可以直接去做"
You know,sometimes,easier said than done.
有时说起来容易 做起来难
However,very often,
但通常
you know,jumping into the water,just doing it,
例如跳入水中 这个行为
taking action has the same effect as all the preparation,
做出行动本身 和所有前期准备有一样的效果
or even the better effect,and leads to an upward spiral.
或者效果更好 能形成良性循环
OK.Then we talked about coping and exiting your comfort zone.
然后我们谈到了应对以及退出舒适区
Parents,please close your eyes at this point.Alright.
家长们 你们可以暂时忽视这个
And I ended by talking about attaining your
然后我以找到你们的
'optimum levels of discomfort'.
"最佳不适水平"结束
What does this mean? What does this mean?
这是什么意思 什么意思
So we can look at approaches to change or reactions to change,
我们可以寻找改变的途径或方法
behavioral change along the continuum of tension.
伴随紧张的连续统一体的行为改变
Most of us most of the time are in our comfort zone.
我们大多数人在大多数时候都蜷缩于舒适区
It's great.It's wonderful.However,
这很好 很不错 但是
when we are in the comfort zone,very little change happens.
当我们处于舒适区里时 很少发生变化
If you go beyond that,we get to our stretch zone.
当跳出舒适区 就到了拉伸区
This is what we call the optimal discomfort zone.
也就是最佳不适区
This is where change actually happens.
这就是改变实际发生的地方
Beyond that is the panic zone.
再越过这个就是恐慌区
This is where we have anxiety and difficulty.
此时我们就有了焦虑和困扰
This is the place that is usually unhealthy.
这通常是不健康的区域
Unhealthy for change.
对于改变来说不健康
Because very often,we can go back on where we were before.
因为这时通常我们都会回到原来的状态
You can think about this with a metaphor:
可以打个比方
the comfort zone would be freezing water.
舒适区就像是结冰的水
The stretch zone would be flowing water.
拉伸区就是流动的水
The panic zone would be boiling water.
而恐慌区就是沸腾的水
Again,a lot of movement,
非常躁动
but out of control and potentially dangerous.
但难以控制 并且十分危险
The best way to be usually is in the stretch zone.
一般最好是呆在拉伸区里
You'll read about it next week when you read about flow.
下周当你们读到"流动"时会读到这个
Flow is when you have optimal level of arousal,
流动就是当你受到适度的刺激
optimal level of tension.
适度的紧张
When the task that you are doing,or whatever you are doing,
当你做的事 或者别的什么
is not too difficult nor too easy.
既不会太难也不会太简单
See what I did at the end of last class was certainly,
我上节课最后的部分 很显然
as I said,as you saw I hope,out of my comfort zone.
正如我所说 你们所见 就越出了我的舒适区
However,it wasn't enough- well,maybe-
可是它还不足以 可能够了...
but probably not in the panic zone.
但应该还没到恐慌区
Why? Because I already know you-
为什么呢 因为我已经认识你们了
we have been together for over a month.
我们已经在一起一个多月了
It's already passed at the drop date- so,too late for you.
已经过了撤课的最后期限 你们已经来不及了
So I wasn't taking that much of the risk.
所以我也不是冒了很大的风险
It was just stretching.And it was important for me to do...
只是拉伸一下 而且这件事对我很重要
I mean,really personally important for me to do it.
我是说对我个人来说很重要
Because it does stretch me
因为它确实拉伸了我
and get me more in touch with my humanity.
使我更多的接触到了我的人性
Or for example,let's say you want to start an exercise in gym.
或者比方说你要在健身房里锻炼
You realize how important it is.You read the research.
你意识到这很重要 你看了这方面的研究
You are exposed to that research
你得知这方面的研究
and you see it really has an important effect.
你看到它确实有很重要的作用
And you start exercising.
于是你开始锻炼
Well,if you have an exercise for 5 years
如果你已经锻炼了五年
and you got to start running 8 miles a day.
然后你打算开始每天跑八英里
That's a problem.
问题就来了
You are over-stretching.You'll probably get injured.
你拉伸过度了 你可能会受伤
If you continue sitting in front of the TV or playing gameboy,
如果你继续坐在电视前 或者打游戏
that's also not good for change.
那对于改变也不是什么好事
That's the comfort zone perhaps not good.
也就是呆在舒适区也许不是好事
Stretch will be "OK,let me start with walking
拉伸就是"好吧 就从每天
for two miles a day and build it up gradually."
走两英里开始 然后逐渐增加"
Stretch myself,but not too much.
拉伸自己 但不要过度
Or if you think about starting to give lectures to others,
或者如果你想给别人做讲座
paying it forward,in positive psychology or biology,
传递知识 积极心理学或者生物学
whatever your topic is,
无论是什么话题
and you get anxious in front of an audience.
在观众面前你都会紧张
You don't start giving a lecture in Sanders Theatre.
不一定要从Sanders剧院开始
You start initially with your friends,teammates.
可以从你的朋友 队友开始
This is how I start with my squash teammates.
我就是从我的壁球队友开始的
I gave the first lecture to them and then I gave it to my family.
我给他们做了第一次讲座 然后给家人做
Gradually out of the comfort zone.
逐渐走出舒适区
A little bit of stretch and then build it over time.
每次拉伸一点点 然后逐渐增加
This is the health way of approaching change.
这是改变的健康方式
Sometimes though,sometimes though,
但是有时候 有的时候
we have to go to the panic zone.
我们必须要进入恐慌区
why? Because something cannot be changed,
为什么 因为有些东西无法
or almost impossible to change gradually.
或者几乎不可能逐渐地改变
For example,addiction.
例如 成瘾
If I'm addicted to drugs,it's very difficult to say,
如果我是个瘾君子 那就很难说出
"well I'll just have a little bit less,
"我就少注射一点
inject a little bit less today.A little bit less tomorrow."
今天少一点 明天再少一点"
It usually has to be abrupt.And then we are in the boiling realm.
通常都要很突然 然后我们就处于沸腾的区域
Then we are in the panic zone.
就处在恐慌区
Quite literally at times,which is why we need help.
时常都是这样 所以我们才需要帮助
In this area,we need someone to hold us.
在此时我们需要有人抓紧我们
Someone to comfort us.Someone to protect us.
安慰我们 保护我们
Because it is such a volatile zone.
因为这是个如此反复无常的地带
And potentially dangerous.
并且十分危险
But generally,if you want to change,
但一般来说 如果你想改变
the healthy approach to change would be along the stretch zone.
健康的方式就是在拉伸区进行
It's impossible to change in theory.
仅从理论上来说 是不可能改变的
Now I have said it so many times and yet very often people
我已经说了很多遍 但还是经常有
who take the class,as you know,many of them do change.
上了这个课的人 他们中的很多人确实改变了
Many of them do say,
他们中的很多人确实说
"well my life is better today for having taken it."
"上这个课使我的生活变得更美好了"
And other people say,
还有些别的人则说
"well I took the class and it didn't make a difference in my life
"我上了这个课 但它对我的生活没什么影响"
It was a fun experience at times- the pink shirt and others.
"这是个很有趣的经历 粉红T恤之类的"
But it didn't make a real lasting difference in my life."
"但对我的生活没有造成实质而持久的影响"
In every...almost all- not in all cases,but in almost all cases,
在每种...几乎所有 并不是所有 但大多数情况下
it's because it wasn't behavioral change associated
这是因为这改变并不是与态度改变
with the attitudinal change or with the insides
或与内在的理解和认知
or understandings or recognition.
相关联的行为改变
There has to be a bias for action.
一定会存在着行动偏向
And that bias for action- just name a few examples:
关于行动偏向 举几个例子
to increase confidence- we do it by taking risks,
为了增加自信 我们得冒险
not by talking and thinking about,
而不是说一下 或者想一下
or standing in front of the mirror and say to myself:
或者站在镜子前对自己说
"I have a lot of confidence.I have self-esteem.
"我非常自信 我有自尊"
I'm great.I'm terrific.I'm gorgeous." Not enough.
"我很棒 很好 很伟大" 这都不够
How do we reduce stress in our lives?
我们如何在生活中减轻压力
And we'll talk about it next week.
下周我们会讲这个
By simplifying,by doing less rather than more.
简单点说 就是少做点事 而不是多做点
We'll talk about how actually doing less at times
我们会讲到为什么少做点事其实
doesn't just lead to more happiness,
不仅会带来更多的幸福感
it also leads to more success,
也会带来更大的成功
more creativity as well as productivity.
更多创造力 以及生产力
But we can't reduce the stress in theory.
但我们不能在理论上减少压力
Chipping away through the gratefulness,
要借由感恩走出阴影
creating more positive channels,
创造更多积极的渠道
becoming more of a benefit finder over time.
逐渐成为积极者
It takes time.Doesn't happen overnight.
这需要时间 不是一夜之间的事
The nice thing though is that when we are afraid,
但好的一面是 当我们害怕时
when we think it's too much for us to take certain action,
当我们觉得难以采取特定行动时
we can use our internal simulator.
我们可以运用内部模拟器
Remember the mind doesn't know the difference
还记得吧 大脑是无法分辨
between the real thing and the imaginary thing?
真实和假想的东西的
And if we imagine something,if we are in the CBT language,
如果我们想象某物 用认知行为治疗的话来说
if we engage in exposure,
在我们受到刺激时
either through the imagination or through actual action,
不管是通过想象还是实际行为
when we engage in exposure,over time,we become confident,
如果我们受到刺激 久而久之 我们就会变得自信
which as I told you,what I do,preparing for lectures,
就像我告诉你们的一样 为讲座做准备
seeing myself,doing it in my mind's eye,
看到我自己 在我的脑海中进行这件事
and the mind doesn't know the difference,
我的大脑并不知道在真实和想象之间
in the real and in the imagined.
有什么区别
And overtime,we'll become more confident.
逐渐地我们就变得更自信了
It's a good start.It's not enough.
这是个好的开始 但这不够
But certainly goes hand in hand
但很显然是很实用
and a very useful technique to explore and to try.
也很有益的 可供尝试和探索的方法
So all this is well and good.
这些都很好理解
I'm sure some of you are thinking about,
我想你们有些人肯定在想
and actually some came after class last time
事实上上节课后有些人
and talked to me about it and said,
来找我谈过 说
"OK,so we know action is important,but there is a problem.
"我们知道行动很重要 但有个问题"
And the problem is that I don't or many people don't have
"问题在于我 或者许多人都没有"
enough discipline to engage in this action,
"足够的自律来完成这个行动"
to get out and run three times or five times a week.
"来保证每周跑三次或者五次步"
We are lazy.
"我们很懒"
It's much more fun playing with our Nintendo
"玩游戏更有意思一些"
than going and doing yoga for an hour,at least initially.
"相比于做一小时瑜伽 至少一开始是这样"
So I don't have enough discipline for change.
"所以我没有足够的自律性来改变"
I just want a quick show of hands.Be honest.
我想让你们快速地举个手 说实话
Put up your hand if you believe that
举起手来 如果你相信
if you had more self-discipline-
假使你能更自律
now you may have a lot of self-discipline
现在你们可能非常自律
or very little self-discipline,
也可能很不自律
but if you had more self-discipline,
但假使你能更自律
you could potentially be happier and/or more successful.
你就可以更幸福或更成功
If you had more self-discipline? Be honest.
假使你能更自律 说实话
I mean my hand is very much up.
我的手可是举得很高的
OK,so it's most people think that.
好 大多数人都这么觉得
So I have good news for you and bad news for you.
我有一个好消息和一个坏消息要告诉你们
I'll start with the bad,
从坏消息开始吧
because I'd like to finish on the positive.
因为我喜欢积极的结尾
So the bad news is
那么坏消息是
you aren't going to get any more self-discipline.
你们不会获得更多的自律
What you have is what you got and what you will get.
你现在拥有的就将是全部
That's it.Sorry.Tough luck.
就是这样 抱歉 真倒霉
Most people,most people,overwhelmingly majority of people
大多数人 绝大多数的人
think they need or want more self-discipline
认为他们需要并且想要更加自律
and believe that they don't have enough.
认为他们现有的自律不够
And most,
大多数
just about all people cannot get any more self-discipline.
几乎所有人都无法得到更多自律性
Nature.That's it.So that's the bad news.
事实就是这样 这就是坏消息
The good news: it's actually not that important,
好消息是 更多的自律事实上并不重要
neither for success,nor for happiness.
不管是对于成功或是幸福感
You can be more successful and happier with the self-discipline
就用你现在已有的自律性 你也可以
that you currently have.
变得更成功 更幸福
How? If you change your focus from relying on self-discipline
怎么做呢 如果你把注意力从依靠自律性
for bringing about change to introducing rituals.
来获得改变 转到引入例行公事上来
Changing your focus from self-discipline to rituals.
将你的注意力从自律转向例行公事
I am going to talk about an idea now that is part of...
我接下来要讲的一个理念
that is talked about in greater length
完整的叙述来自于
in The Power of Full Engagement by Jim Loehr and Tony Schwartz.
Jim Loehr和Tony Schwartz所著的《精力管理》
An excellent,excellent book.
一本非常非常好的书
And what they are talking about is essentially a paradigm shift.
他们所说的本质上是一种思维转换
A paradigm shift,
思维转换
where we need to stop trying to get more self-discipline,
就是我们要停止试图得到更多的自律
because that,in and of itself is not enough for success,
因为自律本身对于成功 对于幸福
for well-being,for change.
对于改变来说是不够的
And it's because people rely on self-discipline for change.
正是由于人们依赖于自律来获得改变
That is the reason why
这就是为什么
most organizational as well as individual change efforts fail.
许多组织及个人的尝试改变的努力失败了
So let me share with you a fun study.
让我和你们分享一个有趣的研究吧
This was done by Roy Baumeister,
这个研究是Roy Baumeister做的
one of the leading social psychologists of the 20th
二十世纪以及二十一世纪初最卓越的
and the beginning of the 21st century.
社会心理学家之一
Great researcher.Here was what he did.
非常伟大的研究者 他所做的研究如下
He brought in a group of people individually.
他逐个把一组人带进来
So the person walks into the experiment.
于是那个人来进行试验
And they are told,once again,"you have to wait in this room,
然后同样告诉他们 "你得在这个房间等候
waiting room for the experiment to start.
在这个等候室里等待实验开始"
So the person sits down.
于是那个人坐下来
There is a table right next to that person.
在他旁边有张桌子
And on the table,there's a bowl.
桌上放了一个碗
And in the bowl,there are freshly baked chocolate chip cookies.
碗里装着刚烤好的巧克力脆饼
Just came out of the oven.
新鲜出炉的那种
Smell the aroma,engulfing them.
芳香萦绕在空气里
You know like those cartoons,going into their nose.
就像动画片里画的 飘进他们的鼻子里
Phenomenal smell.
无比的香味
They are sitting there,
他们就坐在那儿
next to the chocolate chip cookies that are in a bowl.
正挨着装巧克力脆饼的碗
The experimenter puts and says,
试验者然后说
"I'll come and pick you about 10 minutes for the experiment."
"我会在约十分钟后回来叫你去参加试验"
They walk out.And as they are walking out,they tell them,
他们走出去 出去之前对受试者说
"oh just by the way,these chocolate chip cookies,
"顺便提一下 这些巧克力脆饼"
they are for the next experiment.
"是为下一个试验所准备的"
So if you don't mind,don't touch them."
"所以如果你不介意的话 最好不要动它"
So you are sitting there,almost dying,
于是你就坐在那儿 非常渴望
but you are not touching it.
但就是不能碰它
And ten minutes later,
十分钟之后
the experimenter does come in,takes you to the experiment.
试验者确实回来了 带你去参加试验
The experiment is very difficult.
这个试验非常难
Very difficult.Very difficult test that you need to take.
你要进行非常非常难的测试
A test that most people don't solve
大多数人都无法通过这个测试
and requires a lot of perseverance and hard work.
并且这需要大量的坚持和努力
But most people,
但大多数人
even with perseverance and hard work do not solve it.
即使拥有坚持和努力也没法通过
So the outcome measure,
所以评估结果时
what the researcher is interested in is mostly
研究者感兴趣的是
how much did you persevere before giving up on that test.
在放弃测试前 你坚持了多久
How much did you persevere before giving up on that test?
That was the outcome measure,the dependent variable.
这才是对结果的评估 才是因变量
Second group,randomly picked,come into the same room,
第二组随机挑选的人 进入同样的房间
sitting on the same chair,have the same bowl on the table.
坐在同一把椅子上 旁边桌上放着相同的碗
But instead of chocolate chip cookies,
但里面装的不是巧克力脆饼
what they have in the bowl are red beetroots.
而是甜菜根
Freshly baked.Just came out of the oven.
刚烤好 新鲜出炉
And they are sitting there.
他们就坐在那儿
And the experimenter is about to walk out,says,
然后试验者正要走出去 说
"just one more thing.
"还有一件事"
If you don't mind,don't touch those beetroots.
"如果你不介意的话 别碰这些甜菜根"
They are for the next experiment." OK.Fine.
"这是为了下一个试验准备的" 好
So you are sitting there for 10 minutes.
你坐在那儿坐了十分钟
10 minutes later,the experimenter comes in,
十分钟后 试验者进来了
takes you to the "real" experiment.
带你去参加"真正的"试验
Sitting down,you take the exact same test.
你坐下来做了跟之前那个一模一样的测试
The exact same puzzle.
完全一样的谜题
And once again,how long will you persevere before giving up?
然后再次看看 放弃测试之前你能坚持多久
Think about for yourself for a second.
你们自己想一下
Who do you think persevered more?
你们觉得哪一组能坚持得久一些
The chocolate chip cookies group? Or the beetroots group?
巧克力脆饼组还是甜菜根组
Think for yourself for a second.
你们自己想一下
By the way,I guessed wrong when I answered this question.OK.
顺便说一下 我在回答这个问题时猜错了
Significantly more perseverance- significantly more,
有一组显著地坚持得更久 显著地更久
wasn't close-
而不是细微差别
the group that had the beetroots persevered a lot more.
甜菜根那组显著地坚持得更久
Why? I wouldn't understand.
为什么 当时我也不理解
The mechanism-
这个机制...
and he did some more experiment to explain the mechanism.
他还做了些其他试验来解释这个机制
It's because the chocolate chip cookie group
这是因为巧克力脆饼组
had used self-discipline not to touch the cookies,
已经用了自律来阻止自己动饼干
though (inaudible) they really wanted to touch it.
虽然他们十分想碰它
But they couldn't.So they used their quota of self-discipline.
但他们不能碰 所以他们已经用了那份自律了
And when they went into the "real" experiment,
等他们去参加"真正的"试验时
what happened was that they had little or no self-discipline left
他们就几乎不剩什么自律了
And that,that maze,that experiment,
而那个迷宫 那个试验
that test required a lot of self-discipline.
那个测试需要大量的自律
The point of this study is
这个研究所要告诉我们的是
we all have limited amount of self-discipline.
我们都只有有限量的自律
And the question is what do we used it on.
问题在于我们将它用在了哪里
Another question for you.
再问你们个问题
How many people here have,
在座有多少人
those of you who did set new year resolutions?
确实制订过新年计划的?
Put your hand up if you fulfilled every single one
如果你们完成了每一个为自己
of the new year's resolutions that you ever set for yourself.
制订的新年计划的 请举手
Put your hand up.
举起手来
Every single new year's resolution,
每一个新年计划
if you did set new year resolutions.
如果你确实制订过的话
A bit higher,please.Well,I certainly didn't.
请举高点 好吧 我显然没有
But here's another question for you.
我还想问个问题
How many people here...this is an important question,
在座有多少人... 这个问题很重要
so please,please put your hand up if the answer is affirmative.
所以如果你的答案是肯定的 一定要举手
How many people here brush their teeth this morning?
在座有多少人今天早上刷了牙
Put your hand up high.Phew! I'm glad to see this.
举高你们的手 很高兴看到这个结果
You can all talk to me after,real close.
你们可以课后找我聊聊
So let me just imagine what happened this morning,this scenario.
让我来想像一下今早上的场景吧
So you got up in the morning.You were tired.
你早上起床 十分疲倦
And then you said to yourself,
然后你对自己说
"OK,today is the day.Today is the day.
"好 就是今天 就是今天"
I am going to do it! I am going to brush my teeth this morning!"
"我要去做 我今天早上要刷牙"
Right? And to really motivate you as you got out of bed :
对吗 你起床后真正给你动力的
Here I come now! I mean,here I come to brush...
我就来了 我就来刷牙了
And you brush your teeth,right? Today is the day!
你也刷牙对吧 就是今天
Because I have 1504! I'm going to brush my teeth!
因为今天我要上课 我要刷牙
Yes! No,of course not.
不 当然不是这样
You know,you rolled off the bed- you know,barely alive.
你滚下床 几乎睁不开眼
You probably don't remember you brushed your teeth,
你可能都不记得你刷了牙
because you were asleep still.
因为你还是像梦游一样
You know why? Why did everyone,
为什么 为什么所有人
I think,I hope everyone brush their teeth this morning,
我觉得所有人今天早上都刷了牙
whereas no one,no one person out of more than 600 students
而没有人 六百个学生里没有一个
fulfilled their new year's resolutions? Why?
实现了他们的新年计划 为什么
Because new year resolutions rely on self-discipline.
因为新年计划依赖于自律
Brushing our teeth relies on a ritual.
而刷牙是例行公事
We do it everyday.It's automatic.
我们每天都做 几乎是自动的
Now there are rituals- we know brushing our teeth is important.
这就是例行公事 我们都知道刷牙很重要
People won't talk to us if we don't.
如果不刷牙别人就不会跟我们说话
But we also know that physical exercise is very important.
但我们也知道锻炼很重要
And yet most people in the world,
而世界上许多人
not at Harvard,but in the world,
不是就哈佛来说 而是整个世界
don't do physical exercise and pay very high price for it.
不做锻炼 并为此付出了很大的代价
You know it always amazed me
我经常感到惊讶
when people used to comment on my incredible self-discipline
当别人夸我有不可思议的自律时
when I was a squash player.
那时我还是个壁球运动员
It always amazed me
这经常让我很惊讶
because I don't see myself as a person with self-discipline.
因为我不觉得我是一个有自律的人
You know we don't have chocolate chip cookies at home.
我们家是没有巧克力脆饼的
And if we do,Tommy hides them.
即使有也会被Tommy藏起来
Because if there were,they would disappear two minutes later.
因为如果有 它们两分钟后就会消失
Zero self-discipline when it comes to these things.
在这些方面我的自律为零
And yet,with squash,I did have,well people thought
但对于壁球 我确实... 人们觉得
and what I thought for many years- self-discipline.
我也这么觉得了好多年 ---我很自律
Because I would get up in the morning and go for my run.
因为我早上很早起床去跑步
I would then go to school and after school,straight to the court
然后去学校 放学之后直接去球场
have a session with my coach- regular session with my coach,
和教练进行训练 常规训练
then play games,matches,and then as you can see,
然后打比赛 然后如你所见
went to the gym and worked out.
去健身房健身
Every single day.
每一天都是这样
And I went home,did my homework and went to bed.
然后回家 做作业 上床睡觉
It was a ritual.That is what athletes do: they have rituals,
这是例行公事 这正是运动员所做的 例行公事
which is why they are able to maintain
所以他们才能保持
what seems from the outside,such high levels of discipline,
从外界看来似乎是很高水平的自律
at times superhuman's.
有时甚至是非常人的
It's not.It's rituals.
但不是这样 这些是例行公事
Jim Loehr and Tony Schwartz:
Jim Loehr和Tony Schwartz说
"Building rituals requires defining very precise behaviors
"建立例行公事需要定义精确的行为"
and performing them at very specific times ―
"并在特定的时间执行它们"
motivated by deeply held values."
"以深深扎根的价值观为动力"
Let me give you some personal examples.
举一些个人例子
Physical exercise deeply held value for me.
锻炼 深深扎根在我心中的价值观
Has always been,and especially now when I know the research,
一直都是 尤其现在我知道了这个研究
the data on physical exercise.
关于锻炼的数据
So I have a ritual:
所以我有件例行公事
three times a week,for 30 and 40 minutes,I run.
每周跑三次步 每次30到40分钟
After that,after that,do my stretching.
之后我就做伸展练习
I know how important yoga and meditation is for me.
我知道瑜伽和冥想对我有多重要
I have a ritual and I do it.
这对我来说是例行公事
First thing when I wake up in the morning,a few deep breaths-
早上醒来第一件事 深呼吸几次
We'll talk about it more after break.
假期回来后我们会更详细地讲到
It's a ritual.
这是例行公事
Every time when I teach here,
我每次来讲课
every time when I get up in front of the audience,I run before.
每次站在观众前面之前 我都会去跑步
This morning,I ran.
今天早上我跑了步
On Tuesday,I ran twice as hard.
周二时我加倍努力地跑
Why? Because it releases anxiety.It helps me.
为什么 因为这可以缓解压力 这能帮助我
Globally,generally and specifically for the class.
总体来说是这样 对于教这堂课则更是
Another very important value for me: my wife- our relationship.
我还有个很重要的价值观 我和我妻子的关系
See the movie? Hitch? Fantastic movie.
看到这电影了吗 《全民情敌》 很好看的电影
It's a very important value for me.
这对我来说非常重要
And therefore,my wife and I have rituals.
因此我和我妻子有例行公事
And we have two ritual dates a week.
每周例行的两次约会
Now when people hear it,they say,
当别人听说这个时 他们说
"Come on! where is the spontaneity of love?"
"拜托 那爱的真情流露呢"
Well,there is a lot of spontaneity in terms of
对于我们在约会中所做的事
what we do during these dates.
确实有自发的真情流露
But the dates are set in stone.
但约会的时间次数是定好的
And if I'm travelling or my wife is travelling,
如果我或我妻子出差旅游
we miss the date,we make up for it after.
错过了约会 那我们就之后再补上
Why? Because if we didn't have this ritual,
为什么 因为如果没有这件例行公事
then we have two dates a decade,as opposed to a week.
我们就不是每周而是每十年两次约会了
And a deeply held value for both of us is our relationship.
我们共有的价值观就是我们的爱情
In our modern world,
在现代社会
there are so many conflicting demands in our time.
我们的时代中有许多相互冲突的需求
Rituals are not just important- they are absolutely necessary.
例行公事不但很重要 它们也是必需的
If we are to do the things that are important for us,
如果我们要做对我们重要的
that we care about.
我们所关心的事
Other examples of rituals: writing a thank you note.
别的例行公事的例子 写感谢信
Once a week,once a month.Making a gratitude visit.
每周一次 每月一次 去拜访别人
Once a month,once a month,once every two months.
每月一次 或者每两个月一次
Doing the gratitude exercise on a daily basis.
把感恩变成一件日常的事
These are rituals that we can introduce
这些是我们可以建立的例行公事
and can actually make an important difference.
并且确实有很重要的影响
We also have ritual dinners with the family as a whole.
我们也有例行的全家一起吃的晚餐
So every shabbat dinner,Friday night dinner,
每个安息日晚餐 周五的晚餐
we have together with the family.
都要全家人一起吃
It's a ritual.It's a wonderful ritual.
这是件例行公事 是件很好的例行公事
During the week,we also have dates when we are together,
每周我们都能聚一聚
because family is an important value to us.
因为家庭对我们来说是重要的价值观
Now sometimes,for example,
有时 比如说
because of travel or other reasons,rituals are broken.
因为旅行或者别的原因 打破了例行公事
Then you can make up for it later.
那就之后再补上
They can also be negative rituals.
还有一些反面的例行公事
Three hour of not checking email.
三个小时不查邮箱
I know it's hard.But it's an important ritual.
我知道这很难 但这是很重要的例行公事
And we'll talk about the effect of having our email on constantly
我们会讲到总是查邮件的影响
Because when we are constantly connected to technology,
因为当我们持续和技术相连时
we are often disconnected from the important things in our lives.
就经常会与生活中重要的事脱节
We'll talk about that after break.
假期回来后我们会讲这个
Rituals.Introduce rituals.
例行公事 建立例行公事
One of the fears that people have
人们听到例行公事时的
when they hear about rituals is they say
恐惧之一在于 他们会说
"well that will take away from my productivity.
"这会降低我的生产力"
And if not productivity,creativity." Not so.
"就算不降低生产力 也会降低创造力" 并不是这样
In fact,the exact opposite is the case.
事实恰好相反
If you look,- yeah,this is a historical research-
如果看看... 这是个历史性的研究
if you look at all the great artists,whether it's writers,
如果看看那些伟大的艺术家 不管是作家
the Hemingways,whether it's the Davincis-
海明威 或者是达芬奇
they had a ritual in their life.
他们生活中都有例行公事
And the ritual was,for example,
这例行公事就是 比方说
"from 7 to 10 am in the morning,I write,no matter what",
"早上七点到十点 不论如何我都要写作"
"6 to 10 at night- if I am more of a night person,I paint".
"晚上六点到十点 如果我习惯在夜里工作 我要画画"
They had rituals.And
他们有例行公事
it's because of these rituals that they were able to be creative.
而正是因为这些例行公事 他们才能创造
Because then they could think about their subject materials
因为那样他们就能专注于主题
as opposed to million other things:
而不是万千使他们分心的事物
"Well,maybe I should be doing something else
"也许我该干点别的"
and there are other distractions"- no! There was a ritual.
"有些让我分心的东西" 不 有例行公事在
That's what I did now.
我现在就该干这个
Almost mindless getting there- just like we brush our teeth.
几乎无意识地就去做了 就像我们刷牙一样
But when they were there,there were space,
但一旦他们开始专注 就有了空间
openness to be creative.
有了创造的空间
Now the key is to give yourself time to create the ritual.
现在关键在于花时间来建立例行公事
You see,maintaining a ritual,
你可以看到 保持例行公事
requires some self-discipline,but not a lot.
需要一定的自律 但并不多
Creating a ritual requires a lot of self-discipline.
建立例行公事需要大量自律
Once again,because we go back to our old habits.
因为我们时常会回到旧习惯
Let's do a quick exercise.
做个快速练习吧
So I want you to just take your hands and just fold them.
抱起你们的双臂进行交叠
Fold your hands for a minute.
交叠一会儿
Alright.Now continue folding your hands- only this time,
好了 继续交叠双手 不过这次
in the opposite direction,
用不同的方式
meaning this hand below and this hand above.
也就是这只手换到下面 这只换到上面
Yeah.Yeah.
对 对
I see especially the men are not really getting it.
我可以看到男生都不太懂
But it's OK.
不过没关系
Now how does that feel? Not comfortable right?
感觉如何 不是很舒服对吧
Now this is such a simple movement.
但这只是非常简单的一件事
You know,folding hands!
交叠双手
And yet we feel very uncomfortable- something is wrong here.
我们仍然能感觉到很不舒服 有点不对劲
And we want to go back to our folding before.
我们想回到原来交叉双手的方式
Much more comfortable.
舒服多了
We first make our habits and then our habits make us.OK.
我们塑造习惯 习惯反过来塑造我们
So the key is,
所以关键在于
here we are talking about a very simple change- folding hands.
我们这还只是做了很小的改变 -交叠双手
How much more difficult is it
那要改变那些我们养成了许多年
when we have had habits that we cultivated for many years
对我们的生活更重要的习惯
and are much more significant in our lives?
会有多么难呢
Very difficult to go...to change them.It takes time.
要改变它们非常困难 这需要时间
William James,as I mentioned before,
William James 我之前提到过
says it takes 21 days to change a habit.
说改变习惯需要21天
Loehr and Schwartz in their book,The Power of Full Engagement,
Loehr和Schwartz在他们的《精力管理》一书中
talk about 30 days to change it.
说需要三十天
And of course it depends on what habit.
当然要看要改变的习惯是什么
So give ourselves 30 days to start the gratitude.
给自己三十天开始学会感恩
Give ourselves 30 days
给自己三十天
to build the new ritual of exercising regularly.
来建立经常锻炼的例行公事
And the key is
关键在于
to give yourself no more than one or two rituals each 30 days.
每三十天内不要建立超过两件例行公事
Why? Because as we mentioned earlier,
为什么 因为正如我们之前说的
it takes a lot of self-discipline to create a ritual
建立例行公事需要大量自律
and we don't have much self-discipline,
而我们的自律是有限的
which is why when we have a list of 10 changes that
这也就是为什么我们今天列出十项
we want to introduce in our lives today,we end up doing none.
想要做出的改变 但最终什么也没变
We end up doing none.
最终什么也没变
Because we are over-extending our self-discipline
因为我们过度消耗了自律
and we break down.
最终崩溃了
It takes a lot of discipline to start a ritual,
开始一件例行公事需要大量自律
but once we start it,after a month when it's habituated,
但一旦开始 当一个月后它已成为习惯
when it's grooved in,when the neural pathway has begun to form,
已经铭心刻骨 神经通路已经建立时
then we can move onto the next ritual and introduce it,
我们就可以建立下一件例行公事了
if we are ready.
如果准备好了的话
No more than two.Ideally one ritual.
不要超过两个 最好是一个
Next week in your response paper,
下周你们交的论文中
you are going to choose a ritual,
就要选择一样例行公事
two rituals for this month that hopefully you will,
这个月的两件
you will also introduce.
你们可以写一下
Because there cannot be change without behavioral change.
因为没有行为变化 也就不会有改变
Loehr and Schwartz:
Loehr和Schwartz说
"Incremental change is better than ambitious failure.
"逐步的改变好过雄心勃勃的失败"
Success feeds on itself." We see it on individual level.
"成功建立在成功之上" 可以从个人水平上看到
We see it on organizational level.
可以在组织水平上看到
John Carter from the business school does a lot of work on change
商学院的John Carter做了很多努力
in organizations in the realm of leadership.
来改变领导层的架构
What he talks about a lot is how you need small successes
他经常说你需要小的成功
and then build them these successess.
然后逐渐积累成最终的成功
The Dalai Lama:"There isn't anything that isn't made easier
达赖喇嘛说"唯有长期坚持和熟悉"
through constant familiarity and training.
"方能使事情变得容易"
Through training we can change; we can transform ourselves."
"通过训练我们可以改变 可以重塑自我"
You know,
你们知道
one thing that happened to me when I was an undergraduate.
我还在读大学时发生过一件事
It happened in my sophomore year.
是在我大二的那年
I didn't...I played at the Varsity team.
我没有... 我当时在校队
Didn't have a good season.
没有在赛季里有很好的表现
My sophomore year was burned out- got injured.
我的大二简直一塌糊涂 还受伤了
And couldn't wait for the 1st of March.
我迫不及待地等三月一日
March 1 is the last,and March 2 sometimes,
三月一日是...有时是三月二日
is the last day of the season.
是赛季的最后一天
And I couldn't wait,because after that
我迫不及待等那一天是因为那之后
I could stop playing squash and focus on my studies.
我就可以不打壁球 专心学习了
Then I could get a lot of work done- because with squash,
我就可以做很多事 因为打壁球时
we were at the courts,you know trained physically for two hours
在球场上每天都要训练
but total three hours a day.
两到三小时
Weekends- we were travelling mostly or had matches at home.
周末我们经常要外出或在这里打比赛
Mornings- at least two mornings a week
早上 每周至少两个早晨
we were lifting weights or in the gym.
我们要健身或者举重
So it was rough.A lot of work
这很难捱 积了一大堆作业
and I said I can't wait to have the freedom without squash,
我等不及获得没有壁球的自由
especially giving that I wasn't enjoying that much at that point.
尤其是当时我还不是那么爱打壁球
Can't wait.Not to do anymore and just to focus on my classes.
等不及不再打壁球 专注于我的学习
Catch up on all the readings and writings and stuff.
追上阅读 写作之类的进度
March 1 came.I stopped playing completely.
三月一号到来了 我彻底不再打球
And instead of becoming more productive.
但与高效学习相反
I became far less productive.
我反而效率变低很多
Now I see a lot of you nodding.
我看到你们很多人点头
The athletes know what I am talking about.
运动员们肯定都有同感
Why? Why did I become more,or rather less productive?
为什么 我的效率取决于什么
Procrastination- wow! Skyrocketed.
拖延 哇! 突然升高
Why? Because for years I've been told
为什么 因为许多年来大家都跟我说
I'm a person with self-discipline.
我是一个自律的人
And I started to believe it.
而我也开始相信这一点
Yeah,I have a lot of self-discipline.
对 我确实很自律
Look at me! I trained so hard.I worked,you know,
看看我 我刻苦地训练 训练
when I played on the circus six hours a day.
每天像杂耍一样地训练六个小时
That's a lot of self-discipline!
那可是非常的自律啊
And suddenly,the squash season ended.
然而突然间 壁球赛季结束了
And I said,"alright,let's see this discipline at work!"
我说"好吧 看看这自律的作用吧!"
And I wasn't getting any work done.
但我却什么也没做成
Why? Because I gave up my rituals.
为什么 因为我的例行公事被打破了
You see,during the season,those of you
在赛季中 你们那些
who played varsity or very involved in music or club know that-
在校队的 或是投身于音乐或社团的就知道
when you are investing a lot in a certain organization,
当你在特定组织里投入很多时
your time has to be ritualized.
你的时间必须例行化
So you know you are in practice then or you are ?
那样你就知道你在什么时候该训练 或学习
in these hours,or you are having meetings at these hours.
或者什么时候该开会
And after that you have to go back and work.
那之后你就回去学习
Because you only have two hours to do.
因为你只有两个小时
And you want to get an OK night sleep.
而你又想睡个还算安稳的觉
You have rituals.And you are productive and you are creative.
你有这样的例行日程 就会高效并具有创造力
And suddenly the rituals go away.
突然之间这些例行公事都消失了
You said,"OK now I'm gonna work more".
你说"好了 现在我要更努力学习了"
The exact opposite happens.Because we have a limited amount...
但恰好相反的事出现了 因为我们只有有限的...
It was only when I came to terms of fact
直到我意识到
that I have a limits amount of self-discipline.
我的自律是有限的 这个事实之后
It's only when I came to terms with the human nature-
直到我明白人类本性...
nature should be commanded must be obeyed.
本性就应该被遵循
It was only then that I actually became productive.
那时我才真正开始变得高效率
Because I created new rituals in my life after that.
因为那之后我又建立了新的例行公事
Rituals- very important and significant.
例行公事 非常重要且有意义
The only way for lasting change.
做出持久改变的唯一方法
Let me talk about cognition now.The C.
现在来谈谈认知吧 首字母C的这个词
So we talked about affect- the emotions; we talked about behavior
我们已经谈过情感 也谈过行为
how important that is both acute and gradual.
谈过它有多重要 既是剧烈的也是逐渐的
Let's talk about cognition.
接下来让我们来谈谈认知
We'll talk again about cognitive reconstruction
再次谈谈认知重建
which is the gradual way of bringing about change.
也是造成改变的渐进方式
And then we'll talk about the fast way of bringing about change,
然后我们再谈谈造成改变的快捷方式
which is the Eureka experience,the ah ha moment.
也就是"有了!"的体验 灵光乍现的一刻
So first,cognitive reconstruction.
首先 认知重建
As we mentioned before,an interpretation is a neural pathway.
正如之前说过的 诠释是一种神经通路
If I interpret the world as a fault finder,
如果我像个消极者一样诠释世界
the fortified neural pathway in my brain are the negative ones,
我大脑里的神经通路就会是消极的
these in experience
生活中的体验
and I go immediately to the negative interpretation
我就会消极地进行诠释
and that gets reinforced over time.
然后随时间不断加强
If I'm a merit finder,I would look the exact same experiences
如果我是个积极者 对相同的经历
and interpret them very differently.
就会有非常不同的诠释
Because I have very different neural pathways in the brain.
因为我大脑中的神经通路就非常不同
Of course,
当然了
there are consequences to how we interpret our experiences.
我们如何诠释经历是有不同结果的
Not necessarily that things happen for the best,
不一定会有最好的结果
but as a merit,as a benefit finder- sorry,I change that.
但作为积极者 抱歉我换了个说法
As a benefit finder,looking more at the,
作为积极者 更能看到
at the positive with each experience.
每段人生经历中积极的方面
Now remember the study on the identical twins
回忆一下同卵双胞胎的研究
and how much genes actually matter.
以及其中基因到底有多大影响
That only account for 55% of the variance.
那只能解释55%的差异
So here is the story that's told in many intro to psych textbooks
这是很多心理学入门教材中会提到的故事
And it's about twins who were raised in a same home
是关于双胞胎 在同个家庭中长大
and their father was abusive toward them,toward their mother.
他们的父亲对他们及其妻子都很暴力
He was very often drunk,very often on drugs,
他经常酗酒 吸毒
and really an awful,awful childhood- the worst you can imagine.
非常非常可怕的童年 所能想到的最悲惨的童年
And these twins grow up in that home with that father.
这对双胞胎与父亲一起在这个家庭中长大
And they go off.They leave their home,
然后他们离开了 离开家
run away from home later on in life and they reach the age of 30.
从这个家里逃出去 然后到了三十岁
And then at the age of 30,a psychologist
在他们三十岁时 一个正在
who is doing research on twins goes and visits them.
对双胞胎进行研究的心理学家拜访了他们
And he goes to the first twin.
他先去找了双胞胎里的第一个
And what he sees there: the twin is in a relationship.
他看到的是 这个孩子结婚了
He's abusing his family,very often drunk,very often on drugs.
虐待家人 经常酗酒 吸毒
Then the psychologist is able to find him in
然后心理学家终于找到他
a moment of soberness and says to the twin,
有那么一刻清醒着 然后跟他说
"what's going on? What are you doing? What's happening here?"
"怎么了 你在干什么 发生了什么"
And the twin who knows
那个孩子知道
that the psychologist is doing research on the effect of genes
这心理学家在做关于基因的作用
and the effect of upbringing,says,"you know my father.
以及成长环境的作用的研究 他说"你认识我父亲"
You know the kind of childhood that I endured.
"你知道我经历了怎样的童年"
How do you expect me to be any other way?"
"你还想让我变成怎么样呢"
And the psychologist who knows the effect of upbringing shrugs.
那个知道成长环境的作用的心理学家耸了耸肩
And then he goes to the second twin.
然后他去找了双胞胎里的第二个
The second twin happens to be at the exact same age
第二个孩子和第一个孩子正好是
as the first one.
一样的年纪
He goes to the second twin- also 30 years old,
他去找了第二个孩子 也是三十岁
walks into the house and cannot believe his eyes.
他走进他家 不敢相信自己的眼睛
Such peace.Such equanimity.Such love.
如此和谐 如此平静 如此充满爱
Between him and his wife,and the kids.
充盈在他和他妻子 以及他孩子之间
He's doing well in his career,doing well with his family.
他事业有成 家庭美满
He comes back again after a while- see maybe there was a fluke;
他后来过了段时间再去找他 因为这可能只是个巧合
maybe he's putting on a show,but no- it's the real thing.
也许他只是装出来的 但不是 这是真的
Phenomenal family life.Phenomenal professional life.
事业有成 家庭美满
And he goes to him and says,in disbelief,"how?"
他找到这孩子 难以置信地问"为什么"
Now the twin also knows that he's doing research and he says,
这个孩子也知道他的研究内容 他说
"what do you mean 'how'? You know my father.
"什么'为什么' 你认识我父亲的"
You know how I was raised.You know what he did to us.
"你知道我是怎么长大的 你知道他对我们做了什么"
How do you expect me to be any other way?
"你还想让我变成怎么样呢"
I know how much he hurt us.
"我知道他对我们的伤害有多深"
How do you expect me to be any other way like him?"
"你还想让我变成他那样吗"
Same experiences.Monozygotic twins.Same genes.
同样的经历 同卵双胞胎 同样的基因
Radically different interpretation: one continuing the hell
迥然相异的诠释 一个延续了
that he endured as a child; the other creating a heaven.
他儿时的地狱 另一个则创造了天堂
All because of interpretation.
都是因为诠释的不同
What do you do with it? Well,I have no choice.
应该怎么做 我别无选择
This is the way I was raised.
我就是这样长大的
This is the model- passive victim.
那就是榜样 被动的受害者说
The other- I'm not going to be like that.
另一个则是 我不要变成这样
I'm not going to be like my father- active agent.
我不要像我父亲那样 主动的创造者
So much of it is a matter of interpretation.
这都是因为诠释的不同
Happiness,wellbeing,as we mentioned many times before,
快乐 幸福 正如我们之前多次提到的
is not so much contingent on external circumstances,
并不那么依赖外部的条件
not so much contingent on our status
不在于我们的地位
or the status of our bank account.
或是银行账户的状况
It's contingent on our state of mind.
而是在于我们内心的想法
The thing that you'll remember though is that
你们必须记住的是
there are no shortcuts unfortunately.
很不幸 幸福是没有捷径的
There are no quick fixes unfortunately.
很不幸没有简便的方法
If there were,I promise you I would've told you.
如果有 我保证我会告诉你们的
If I find out next week about a shortcut,
如果我下周找到条捷径
even if it's over spring break,you'll get an email from me.
即便是在春假之后 你们一定会收到我的邮件的
But I don't think there are.And very often,
但我不觉得会有的 通常
the hope of finding a quick fix leads to more unhappiness.
寄希望于找到捷径通常导致更多的不快乐
Here are some examples of cognitive reconstruction.
举几个认知重建的例子
This is work done by Tomaka on
这是由Tomaka进行的研究
whether we perceive activity as a challenge or as a threat.
关于我们将活动视为挑战还是威胁
Because we can perceive the exact same activity
因为对同一种活动
and cognitively reconstruct our understanding of it.
我们可以从认知上重建对其的理解
So let me give you an example.
我给你们举个例子
When I,after being thrown out of Cambridge,
当我... 被剑桥拒掉之后
I applied for PHD programs.
我当时申请了博士项目
One of the programs I applied to is here.
这里是我申请的其中一个地方
I was hoping to get in.
我很希望能入选
And when I got in,I wanted to come back,because overall,
我进来之后 我想回来是因为总体来说
I had a very good experience here as an undergrad,
在这里读大学时我挺开心的
with all the difficulties and hardship,
即便有很多困难和困扰
I was glad,wanting to be back.
我仍然很愉快 很想回来
And when I got in,
在我进来之后
you know suddenly I became a little bit concerned.
我突然开始有点担心了
Because I said-
因为我说
you know I experienced a lot of anxiety as an undergrad.
我大学时经历了很多焦虑
A lot of anxiety as an undergrad.
大学时经历了很多焦虑
And I said,I don't want to relive that again.
我说 我不想再过那样的生活了
Maybe I should go else where.
也许我应该去点别的地方
And then I turned around and I said,
然后我回过头来 说
"OK.Instead of looking at Harvard as a threat,to me,to my calm.
"好吧 哈佛不是对我的冷静心态的威胁"
I'm going to look at it as a challenge."
"相反我要把它当成一次挑战"
And my challenge became explicitly-
这挑战变得很明确
I mean I wrote it in my journal,
我在日记里这样写
wrote about it,thought about it explicitly.
明确地想过并写下来
My goal over the six years that I got my PHD was to maintain calm
我博士的六年里 目标是要保持冷静
Because I said to myself,"if I can maintain calm at Harvard,
因为我对自己说 "如果我能在哈佛保持冷静"
I can maintain calm anywhere."
"就可以在任何地方保持冷静"
And I worked on it.I really worked on it.
然后我朝着这个目标努力 非常努力
And it became a challenge and just that change helped me
这确实变成了挑战 而正是这个改变使我
get so much more out of my experience here as a graduate student.
从在这里的研究生经历获得了更多
Even through the hardships,
即便遇到困难
the generals and the failures,and the anxiety.
各种各样的挫折失败 以及焦虑
But overall- a much better experience.
但总体来说 还是很好的经历
Recently I just did it.
我最近也做了这样的事
So you know,once in a while I travel right after class.
有时我刚下课就会去别的地方
So three weeks ago,I travelled to Florida.
三周前我去了佛罗里达
And I have a very important talk there
在那里进行了一次重要的谈话
with the company that I really wanted to work with.
是和一家我非常想进的公司
It was my first event there.Company that I cared about.
那是我的第一次会谈 是我梦寐以求的公司
And I think it is doing fantastic things around the world
我觉得这家公司做的事很不错
and I really want it to do well.
我非常希望能够顺利
And I felt a lot of anxiety before that talk.
在谈话之前我非常焦虑
And I cognitively reconstructed it.
然后我对它进行了认知重建
I said,"OK.It's anxiety inducing,
我说"好吧 这确实让人很焦虑"
permission to be human experience,
"准许自己为人"
but let's look at it as a challenge."
"把它当成一次挑战"
That I have this wonderful opportunity to speak
我有这么好的机会能和
to such a great company,such wonderful people.
这么棒的公司 这么棒的人对话
I'm going to make the best of it.
我一定得好好珍惜
Turned it from a threat into a challenge,into opportunity.
将它从威胁转化为挑战 转化为机会
And that made a big difference in my approach to it.
这对我起到了极大的影响
Think about as in your life.
想想你们自己
What is it? Is it a play you want to try out for?
有没有这样的事 是你要打的一场比赛吗?
Is it someone you want to ask out? Is it speaking up in section?
是你想约出去的人吗 是在公众面前说话吗
This is a study those
这有个学心理学1或者
who take Psych 1 or Psych 15 have encountered that,
心理学15的同学会学到的研究
the work of Schachter & Singer,back in early 60s.Today
由Schachter和Singer在60年代早期做的
it would never be able to get this past the ethics committee.
今天伦理道德委员会肯定不会批准的
Just like Milgram wouldn't be able to get his study passed.
就像Milgram的研究肯定不会被批准一样
Here was what they did.
他们所做的实验如下
So they brought people into the experiment
他们让人们参与实验
and injected them with epinephrine.
给他们注射肾上腺素
Epinephrine arouses the body.
肾上腺素可以使机体兴奋
It...shots of adrenaline.
注射肾上腺素
But they thought it was just vitamin C.
但受试者以为打的只是维生素C
They didn't know it's epinephrine.
他们不知道这是肾上腺素
And then they were sitting in the experiment,
然后他们就坐着
waiting again for the "real" experiment.
等待"真正的"实验
They were sitting in the waiting room.
他们坐在休息室里
And while they were sitting
正当他们等着时
they were asked to fill out a questionnaire.
试验者要求他们填一份调查问卷
Now remember,they just got a shot of adrenaline,
记住他们刚被注射了肾上腺素
but they didn't know they got a shot of adrenaline.
但他们并不知道被注射了肾上腺素
So they were sitting,filling in a questionnaire.
于是他们就坐着填调查问卷
And in the first condition,
在第一种条件下
the questionnaire had very provocative questions,
问卷里有很刺激性的题目
to say the least.
可以这样说
For example,one of these questions was so
比如说 其中有一道是这样的
"how many men did your mom sleep with
"你妈妈和你爸爸结婚前
before she got married to your dad?"
和多少男人上过床"
That's one of the que...You know
这是问卷的其中一道...
they would never be able to get away with this study today,
他们的研究放在今天一定不会被批准的
but you know,back in the 60s.So they were answering this.
但那是在六十年代 所以他们填了调查问卷
Now next to them,next to them,there is a confederate-
而在他们旁边 旁边有一个同谋者
someone who they don't know is part of the study.
他们不知道他是实验的一部分
And this guy is going ballistic.
而这个人暴跳如雷
"How dare they" You know...Really getting angry.
"他们怎么敢这么问" 非常非常生气
And you get angry too.
于是你也变得很生气
And you get even angrier than the control group
你甚至比对照组更加愤怒
who went through the exact same thing,
对照组经历了同样的事
except for the fact that they didn't get the injection.
但他们并未注射肾上腺素
So what they did was they looked,
所以受试者看到自己
they saw their bodies is getting very aroused
看到自己的机体非常兴奋
and they interpreted this arousal as "oh I must be really angry".
而他们将这种兴奋诠释为"噢 我一定是太愤怒了"
And they really did get,even angrier than they would have.
而他们确实变得更愤怒了 比原本应该愤怒的程度更高
They got angry in the control group as well
对照组也很愤怒
but less angry than those who were injected the epinephrine.
但没有那些注射了肾上腺素的那么愤怒
Now second condition.Also injected.
而第二种条件下 同样接受了注射
Had a questionnaire without any provocative questions.
做了个没有什么刺激性问题的问卷
And next to them there was again a confederate,
他们旁边也坐了个同谋者
whom they thought was also doing the experiment.
他们也以为他是来做实验的
And that confederate found by happenstance,
这个同谋者偶然发现
a hula hoop on the floor and started to shake it.
地上有个呼啦圈 然后就开始摇呼啦圈
You know,dance and...
跳啊摇啊...
You know it was going crazy- they are happy and laughing.
接着就有点疯狂了 他们很高兴 都在笑
And the person who was just injected epinephrine went wild.
而刚被注射了肾上腺素的人变得很疯狂
So happy and joyous- much more happy than the control group,
十分欢腾愉悦 比对照组快乐多了
who were in the room with a person dancing with a hula hoop,
对照组也和摇呼啦圈的人共处一室
but did not get the injection.
只是没有注射肾上腺素
In other words,he interpreted the raising in adrenaline
也就是说 他把肾上腺素的升高诠释为
"Oh I must be really happy now".And they were really happier.
"噢 我一定是太开心了" 而他们确实变开心了
In other words,very often it's the interpretation- in this case,
换句话说 经常都是由于诠释的不同 在这个试验中
of a physical symptom that determines what we will feel.
对某种生理症状的诠释 决定了我们的感觉
Joy or anger.Because they are quite similar.
愉悦或愤怒 因为它们非常相似
In both of them,there is an adrenaline rush.
两者都涉及肾上腺素的急剧升高
So how do we interpret a situation as an arousal or,
所以我们是怎样把一个情况诠释为兴奋
as euphoria or as anger?
或者愉悦 或者愤怒的呢?
Here's another study.
这里还有另一个研究
This is done by Lee Ross and his colleagues.
是由Lee Ross及他的同事做的
They asked people,college students- he's from Stanford-
他们邀请大学生... 他来自斯坦福
college students to volunteer their most generous,
大学生说出他们最慷慨
benevolent friends to name them and their most competitive,
最善心的朋友 以及他们最好胜
cut-throat friends and tell them who they are.
最凶狠的朋友 然后告知他们是谁
And they contacted them to be part of the study.
然后他们联系这些人作为实验的一部分
And what they wanted to see was their behavior in a situation
他们想知道的是在一个可以选择合作
in a game where you can cooperate or you can be competitive.
也可以选择竞争的游戏中 他们的行为是怎样的
The intervention was that these students,
所做的干预是将这些学生
randomly divided into two groups.
随机地分为两组
And in the two groups,
在这两组中
there were people who were deemed very competitive
有被认为很好胜的人
or people who were deemed very generous and benevolent.
也有被认为很慷慨大方的人
And in the second group,
在另一个组中
same thing- half of the people were very generous and benevolent;
也是一样 一半人慷慨大方
half of the people were very,very competitive and cut-throat,
另一半人非常好胜凶狠
as perceived by their friends.
至少他们的朋友是这样觉得的
And in the first group,they got a game and the game was called
第一组要玩一个游戏 这游戏叫做
"the community game".
"社区游戏"
And the second group got the exact same game,the game
第二组也要玩一模一样的游戏
where you have the opportunity either to cooperate or to compete.
游戏中你可以合作也可以竞争
But instead of a community game,
但不叫做社区游戏
even though it was the exact same game,
即便是一模一样的
it was called "Wall Street game".
相反被叫做了"街头游戏"（比较暴力的游戏总称）
And they wanted to see how many people cooperate versus
他们想看看有多少人会合作
how many people compete.
有多少人会竞争
And they wanted to see what predicts it.
他们也想看看是什么决定了这选择
Well,whether the kids,the participants,
不论这些学生 受试者
were deemed cooperative or competitive,predicted nothing.
是被认为合作性或者竞争性的 都和结果没关系
Nothing.Whether or not they would compete or cooperate.
毫无关系 他们是选择竞争还是合作
What predicted everything was whether
真正决定一切的是
they were in the "community game" or in the "Wall Street game".
他们玩的是"社区游戏"还是"华尔街游戏"
If they were in the "community game",
如果他们玩的是"社区游戏"
they were much more likely to cooperate.
他们更倾向于合作
If they were in the "Wall Street game",
如果他们玩的是"华尔街游戏"
whether they were generous,benevolent,
不论他们是慷慨善良
or cut-throat,competitive,
还是好胜凶狠
they were much more likely to be cut-throat and competitive.
都会更倾向于凶狠而具竞争性
In other words,how we frame a situation-
换句话说 如何表述一个境况
community,Wall Street- can make all the difference.
"社区"或"华尔街" 会起到很大的作用
Threat,opportunity- maybe the exact same thing.
威胁 机会 也许也正是如此
How we frame it can make all the difference.
我们如何表述决定了所有区别
This is a study done by one...(part missing)...the quest.
这个实验是由... (部分丢失)
A very important question which is
一个很重要的问题在于
how can we raise the level of volunteerism,at Harvard and beyond
我们如何提高志愿者精神 不管在哈佛还是别的地方
And the wonderful answer that she came up with is
她想到的一个很棒的答案就是
let's get students as well as people in society at large to
使学生们及社会上的人
reframe how we look at volunteering,
重新审视志愿工作
rather than as duty,something I have to do.
不要把它当成义务 我必须做的事
Why don't I look at it as a privilege?
为什么不能将它视为一种荣幸呢
I have the privilege of helping.And it is a real privilege.
我很荣幸能帮助别人 这确实是种荣幸
Remember the study on kindness?
还记得对善良的研究吗
One of the best interventions for wellbeing.
幸福的最大来源之一
It is a real privilege to give,to help.
给予和帮助确实是种荣幸
And when people reframe this,
如果人们这样重新审视
they are much more likely to volunteer.
他们就会更愿意做志愿者
This has implications for child rearing.
这对抚养孩子有意义
This has implications,of course,for education.
当然 对教育也有意义
It has implications for society as a whole.
对社会整体有意义
This is a topic I am going to talk about a lot.
这是我即将深入讨论的一个话题
I am going to dedicate much time when we discuss relationships.
我会花很多时间讨论情感关系
But just very briefly,this understanding for me transformed,
不过先简要地提提 这个理解改变了
literally transformed my relationship with my wife.
真的改变了我和我妻子的关系
It transformed...
它改变了
It is transforming my relationship with my friends,
它正在改变我和我朋友的关系
as well as students and colleagues.
以及我的学生和同事
You see,we go into a relationship.
我们卷入一段关系
Most people think that important thing about relationship
大多数人觉得情感关系的重要之处在于
is that we are validated,as we get pads on our back.
我们可以得到认可 有人能在背后做支柱
Now that's important in our relationship.
这在我们的关系中确实是重要的
Surely important to be validated in any relationship,
得到认可很重要 在任何关系中都是如此
whether it's with students/teacher,whether it's with friends,
不管是师生之间 朋友之间
certainly in romantic relationship.
当然也在爱人之间
However,what David Schnarch talks about is that primarily
但是David Schnarch想说的是
if we want long-term,successful,thriving,
如果我们想要长期的 成功的 健康的
passionate relationships,the first objective,
有激情的关系 那首要目标
the primary objective is to go into relationship to be known.
最基本的目标是通过关系被了解
To be known,rather than to be validated,
被了解 而不是得到认可
meaning going in there and saying
也就是说 你想着
"OK so how can my partner get to know me even better?"
"我的伙伴如何才能更了解我呢"
Doing it gradually of course.
当然了 要循序渐进
On the first date,you don't want to reveal all your secrets.
在第一次约会上 你肯定不会想说出所有秘密
Doing it gradually.
循序渐进
You know,thinking about it,but opening up more and more.
想着这一点 慢慢地敞开心扉
And couples who over time open up more and more are able to
能够逐渐逐渐敞开心扉的夫妇更能够
sustain the relationship as well as their passion,over time.
维持他们的关系以及激情
And again,I am going to talk about much more...
我还会就此讲得更多
I am going to devote two classes at least to relationships.
我会用至少两节课来讲情感关系
This is going to be
这将是
one of the central pillars of successful long-term relationships.
成功的长期关系的中流砥柱之一
Also with the students,the same applies.
对于学生 也是一样适用
You know when I initially started to teach,
我刚开始教书时
I really wanted the validation from the students.
我非常希望得到学生的认可
So how can I have my students perceive me as a good teacher?
我如何能使学生觉得我是个好老师呢
I want them to like me.
我希望他们喜欢我
And you know,that's important for everyone.
这对每个人来说都很重要
We all like to be liked.
我们都希望被喜欢
However,when I switched my focus- and yeah,
但当我转换注意力 对
I still want to be liked-
我仍然希望被喜欢
but my main focus is I want my students to know me.
但我主要的注意力在于我希望学生了解我
I want them to know the topic
我希望他们了解我对这世界
that I'm most passionate about in the world.
最有兴趣和激情的事物
That really changed a lot.It's no longer to be validated,i.e.
这确实改变了我很多 不再是得到认可 也就是说
to appear perfect,but it was to be known as a human being,
变得完美 而是作为一个人被了解
of course- permission to be human.
当然了 准许自己为人
And that actually improved my teaching a great deal
而这实际上大大地促进了我的教学
and I enjoyed it so much more.
我也更喜欢教课了
Because there is so much less pressure on us in a relationship,
因为我们之间的关系不再有那么大的压力
any relationship,when we go in with the intention of being known
不管是什么关系 只要我们抱着被了解的愿望
of expressing rather than impressing.
重在表达而非使人记住
We can feel so much lighter.And the wonderful thing is,
我们会如释重负 而更好的是
that it also makes the relationship so much healthier.
这使得一段关系更健康
But again,much more on it- because it is so important.
我还会讲得更多 因为这非常重要
So important topic.We talked about this a lot.
是非常重要的话题 我们经常讲这个
How do we perceive failure,as a stumbling block?
我们如何理解失败 绊脚石?
A catastrophe? Or as an opportunity? As a growth experience?
灾难? 还是作为一次机会 或成长的经历?
And that can make all the difference.
这都会有很大的区别
We'll talk about it after spring break
春假之后我们会再学习
when we discuss perfectionism and the fear of failure.
我们会讨论完美主义以及对失败的恐惧
And finally,
最后讲一下
the study that you read by Ali Crum and Ellen Langer.
你们读到的Ali Crum和Ellen Langer做的研究
So just give you a little bit background about the study
先给你们讲点这个研究的背景
and I will briefly mention it,hopefully you've read it already.
我会简要地提一提 希望你们都已经读过了
Ali Crum was my student for,since her freshman year.
Ali Crum从大一起就是我的学生
I was her TF when I taught with Phil Stone.
我是她的助教 那时我和Phil Stone一起教学
And then I was her thesis advisor with Ellen Langer.
然后我和Ellen Langer是她的毕业论文导师
And this was the topic of her thesis.
这是她的毕业论文题目
When Ellen Langer came up with the idea for the thesis,
当Ellen Langer提出这个想法时
and she told Ali and me
她告诉我和Ali
"this is what I think would be a very interesting study",
"我觉得这会是个有趣的研究"
I took Ellen aside after the study- after the meeting,
我在会后把Ellen叫到一边
after Ali went away.
在Ali走了之后
And I told her "Ellen I don't think it's fair.
我跟她说"Ellen我觉得这样不公平"
I don't it's fair that Ali will do her thesis on it."
"我觉得让Ali用这个做毕业论文不太公平"
Because the thesis is a very tough experiment-
因为这是个非常困难的实验
you'll hear about it if you haven't read about it in a minute.
如果你们没看过的话 一会儿就会听到了
"If we take a lot of time from her,
"就算我们花费她大量的时间
she's not going to get any results."
"她也不会有任何成果"
Now you can write your senior thesis with getting no result,
现在你们的毕业论文可以没有结果
without getting a result,that's OK.
没有成果也没关系
But I said,"why waste her time,her senior year?"
但我说"干嘛浪费她的时间呢"
And she said to me,"will work." I said to her,"no it won't."
她跟我说"会有结果的" 我说"不会的"
And boy,did it work!
而最后真的有结果
Now I've learned since not to argue with Ellen Langer
我从那时起就学会了不和Ellen Langer争辩
because she has ideas that you would never think would work,
因为她总有你觉得不可能有结果的想法
but they do like the study we mentioned with the 1979
但他们确实很喜欢我们1979年的
"I'm going back to 1959" or with the eye test,
"回到1959"实验 或是那个视力测试
being simply in the flying simulator improves your eyesight.
只是飞行模拟器提升了你的视力
Again,ideas that seem fantastic,but she proves them right.
就是这些看起来很无厘头的想法 她证明它们是正确的
So the same happened here with this study.
这个研究也是如此
The study was Ali went to hotels
这个实验是 Ali去到酒店
and worked with the ladies who were cleaning the hotels.
和酒店的清洁工一起工作
And she went to them to two groups
她分别去跟两组人一起工作
and told both groups the importance of physical exercise.
跟两组人都说了锻炼的重要性
And she said,
她说
"this is,you know,something brought to you by your hotel,
"这是你们酒店搞的
just to show you how important exercise is."
只是为了让你们知道锻炼有多重要"
And then she tested them on all these physical measures,
然后她测试了她们的各项生理指标
whether it was body fat,blood sample-
包括身体脂肪 血液样本
how much fat they had in their blood,weight,
她们血液中有多少脂肪 体重
psychological measures- depression,anxiety,and so on and so on.
还有心理指标 沮丧 焦虑 诸如此类
And what she did was...
而她所做的是
to the one group,she just left them after all these tests.
对于其中一组 她测试完后就不管她们了
The second group,
而另一组
she said to them,and this was the intervention,
她对她们说--这就是干预手段
"you know the work you are doing is actually physical exercise."
"你们所做的工作实际上就是种锻炼"
And she calculated how much calories it takes to pick up sheets,
她计算了收床单所消耗的卡路里
to go like this and then to put it on a bed,
抖床单 然后铺在床上
how much calories it takes to actually vacuum.
用吸尘器清洁要消耗多少卡路里
She estimated all those things
她估算了这所有工作
and then she gave them the statistics of how many calories
然后她给她们看了每天锻炼
you should expend a day doing exercise.
所消耗的卡路里的数据
And she says,"what you are doing is working out actually."
然后她说"你们做的其实正是健身"
This was the intervention.And she went back 8 weeks later.
这是实验的干预 然后她两个月之后再回去
8 weeks later,she ran the exact same tests again.
两个月后 她又进行了同样的测试
And some of the results that she found-
她发现的有些结果
some of them are in the article,others are not.
其中有些结果是预料之中的 有的则不是
Blood pressure decreased significantly.
血压显著下降
The fat in the blood decreased significantly.
血脂显著下降
Body weight,after the 8 weeks,
体重 两个月后
for the intervention group,not for the control group.
实验组而非对照组
Control group: no change over that period!
对照组期间完全没有变化
Body weight decreased significantly.
体重显著下降
Their self-esteem went up.Depression levels went down.
她们的自尊心上升 沮丧程度下降
Anxiety levels went down.And energy levels went up.
焦虑水平下降 精力水平上升
All,as a result.
所有都是这样
Now,she asked,"did you do anything differently?
此时她问"你们做了什么不同的事吗"
Or you are exercising more than you did before?"
"或者你们比以前做了更多的锻炼吗"
No difference between the control group
对照组与实验组之间
and the intervention group.
不存在区别
The only difference was perception.
唯一的区别在于观念
Now they may have worked harder.We don't know.
她们可能工作得更努力了 我们不得而知
It may be just the mind over body.We don't know.
可能只是心理作用 我们不得而知
But the fact is because they reframed,
但事实是由于她们重新审视了
they reconstructed their experience from a chore-
重建了她们自己的经历
"I have to,you know,clean 30 rooms a day"
从"我每天必须清扫三十间房间"
to "this is an exercise; this is good for me".
到"这是种锻炼 这对我有好处"
That made all the difference.
这就是区别所在
Physically as well as psychologically.
既是生理上的也是心理上的
Here is an example of acute change.
这是急剧转变的一个例子
This is the change that happens like a sledgehammer.
这就像一锤子砸下去的变化
And this is the Eureka experience.
这就是"有了!"的经历
There's a lot of talk,a lot of research,
有很多关于"有了!"的经历的讨论
a lot of interest in this area of the Eureka experience,
研究 以及对这个领域的兴趣
the ah ha moment,the insight- so valuable,so important.
灵光乍现的一刻 顿悟--如此珍贵 如此重要
And there's much misunderstanding about it.
而对此也有许多误解
Because people think we suddenly have this insight,not so.
因为人们都觉得这种顿悟是突然产生的 但其实不是
There's a whole process involved.
这是有一整个过程的
And the process begins with immersion.
而这个过程从潜移默化开始
This is when we prepare for the insight.This is when we learn.
这是我们为顿悟准备的时候 是我们学习的时候
Howard Gardner has done a lot of work
Howard Gardner做了许多研究
on extraordinary individuals throughout the world.
关于全世界的成功人士
And what he found is that generally for people
他发现一般来说 对于那些
to become the experts in a field,
在某个领域成为专家
to become Creative in a field,
在某个领域具有创造力的人
they have to have invested at least ten years of very hard work.
他们都会下至少十年的苦功夫
This is the preparation.
这就是准备
This is when you immerse yourself in the material.
这就是你将自己沉浸于那事物之中
Look for the example of Beethoven.
看看贝多芬的例子吧
Those of you who listen to his music and know his trajectory:
如果你们听过他的音乐 知道他的音乐轨迹
Symphony 1 and 2- Mozart.Sounds very similar to Mozart.
第一和第二交响曲 莫扎特 和莫扎特非常相似
3rd Symphony,Eroica- it's Beethoven.
第三交响曲 英雄 就是贝多芬了
He immersed himself a great deal in the music of the day-
他使自己沉浸于当时的音乐
studied it and learned it.and then,after many years,
研究它 学习它 然后许多年之后
was able to become Beethoven and creative,
就能独创自己的风格 具有创造力
and transformed the whole field of music.
以及改变整个音乐领域
Being the first of the Romantics.
作为浪漫主义音乐第一人
Second stage,
第二个阶段
after we prepare- and it takes,again,a lot of hard work,
在准备好之后 这也需要下很多功夫
whether it's preparation that was done by Bill Gates
无论是比尔盖茨所做的准备
when he was skipping class or whether it's Bill Clinton.
即便他是在翘课 还是比尔・克林顿
A lot of preparation before you become an expert in the field
在你成为某领域专家或具有创造力之前
and are able to introduce Creativity-
都要做大量的准备
have that eureka,the insight.
才会有顿悟的一刻
Second stage: incubation.
第二个阶段 孵化
And you see all the creative individuals:
在所有具创造力的人身上都可见
after you immerse yourself in an area,you do nothing.
在你将自己沉浸于事物中之后 你什么也不做
You just allow it to marinate.
你就是沉浸于其中
For example,there's no coincidence that
比方说 并不是巧合
we get some of our best ideas in a shower.
我们许多好点子都出现在洗澡的的时候
It's no coincidence that Archimedes got his best idea in the bath
阿基米德在泡澡时有了伟大的想法也不是巧合
Mozart used to spend hours a day,just driving around Salzburg
莫扎特曾经每天花好多个小时 在萨尔兹堡晃荡
and then suddenly he would have the ah ha experience,the eureka.
然后突然他就顿悟了
He said,"I could hear the symphony in a second."
他说"我突然能听到交响乐"
In a second,he could hear just about everything.
突然他听到了所有
OK.So that's Mozart.
这是莫扎特的故事
But you hear Shakespeare would spend hours driving around
但你也听说过莎士比亚会花很多时间驾着马车
in his carriage and suddenly would have the insight,
到处晃荡 然后突然顿悟
"OK,this is what the story is about."
"故事就应该是这样的"
And then he would go and write it.Incubation is so so important.
然后他就可以去写 孵化是非常非常重要的
J.P.Morgan:
摩根说:
"I can do a year's work in nine months,but not in twelve."
"我可以用九个月内完成一年的工作 但不能用十二个月"
J.P.Morgan understood,you know,
J.P.Morgan他知道 你们知道
arguably be the greatest entrepreneur this country has ever seen,
他可能是美国史上最成功的企业家
understood the importance for creativity of taking time off.
他知道休息对于创造力的重要性
Today,business people,leaders don't take enough time off.
当今的商业精英 领导者们都休息得不够
Because we think it's a waste of time.
因为我们觉得这是浪费时间
We think that if we just sit there and do nothing,
我们认为如果只是坐着什么事也不干
we are really doing nothing.
我们就确实什么事也没干
Well,no.The mind works.
但不是的 思想在工作
The mind works and the mind needs it for the creative insight.
思想在工作 并且思想需要这样 才能获得顿悟
In fact,leaders-
事实上 领导者
and many of you will go into leadership positions-
你们中的很多人都会变成领导者
need time off more than anyone else.
比任何人都需要休息
Because they need to be creative.
因为他们需要创造力
They need to think about the next thing for the company,
他们需要思考公司的未来
for the organization.
机构的未来
Taking time in- invaluable.
适当休息是无价的
Not just for memory,also for creativity.
不只是对记忆力 对于创造力也是一样
One of the things I do when I work with,
我工作时做过一件事
as a consultant in organizations is
作为顾问 就是
I just take the management on a retreat with no agenda.
我会安排一段没有日程安排的时间
We are just going to hang out.And very often,
我们就出去玩 而时常
within as little as half an hour or an hour,ideas begin to come out.
在短短半小时或一小时内 各种各样的点子就会冒出来
Why? Because as the first time,they have time,no coincidence
为什么 因为他们第一次有时间思考
that we often wake up with a solution to a problem we had.
我们常常一觉醒来就想到解决办法 这并非巧合
Because subconscious mind is making connections then.
因为潜意识正在活动
Joseph Campbell:
Joseph Campbell说
"You must have a room,or a certain hour or so a day,
"你必须有个私人空间 或者一天特定的时间段
when you don't know what was in the newspapers that morning,
此时你不知道今早报纸上讲什么
you don't know who your friends are,
不知道你的朋友是谁
you don't know what you owe anybody,
不知道欠了别人什么
you don't know what anybody owes you.
不知道别人欠你什么
This is a place where you can simply experience
这才是你能够静下心体会
and bring forth what you are and what you might be.
感觉到你是谁以及可能是谁的时候
This is the place of creative incubation.
这才是创造力孵化的时候
At first,you may find that nothing happens there.
一开始 你可能发现什么都没有发生
But if you have such a sacred place and use it,
但如果你有一个这样神圣的时刻 并且好好利用它
something eventually will happen." And very often,
奇迹终将会发生" 很经常
it's during this incubation times,it's during these time-ins,
就在这孵化的时间里 在这些休息时间里
during the time when you have the opportunity to reflect,
在这你有机会反思自己的时间里
whether it's on the response paper,
不管是写论文
or just hang out and listen to music.
还是出去玩 听音乐
That's very often when the ah ha moment comes.
灵光乍现的时刻通常都出现在此时
The eureka experience.The one second "I see the symphony".
顿悟的体会 再一次的"我听到了交响乐"
You know,in some way,
某种程度上来说
you can think about an analogy of how this happens.
你可以对此进行一个类比
You can think about stage one.
你可以想想第一个阶段
Or you can think about in a context of a sexual intercourse.
或者你可以当做性交流来想想
Of making love.
比如做爱
Preparation and incubation can be the equivalent to foreplay.
准备和孵化就好比前戏
The eureka experience- the orgasm.
顿悟的时刻就是高潮
Now the important thing to understand about this process
这个过程中要理解的很重要的一点是
is you have to go through preparation,
你必须经过准备和
incubation to get to the eureka experience.
孵化才能到达顿悟的时刻
In other words,you need the foreplay.
换句话说 必须要有前戏
Did you hear that man?
男同学们 你们听见了吗
You need the foreplay to get to the next level.
必须有前戏才能进入下一步
It's important.It's part of the creative process.
这很重要 这是创造力的过程的一部分
It's significant.It's very significant for love.
这意义重大 对于爱情来说意义重大
It's significant also for this process.
对于这个过程来说同样意义重大
And then afterwards,
而这之后
after you've come up with the eureka,that's when you evaluate.
在你顿悟了之后 就是该进行评估的时候
You ask yourself,"is this a good idea? Does it work?
你要问自己"这是个好主意吗 会有用吗
Or is it just something that you know women and..."
还是只是... 你知道的 女人..."
Most ideas,most eureka experiences actually end up not working.
很多主意 很多顿悟的体验 最终都没起作用
And therefore,evaluation is important.
因此评估非常重要
Is this really a good piece?
这确实是好主意吗
Is this really a good idea for a story?- Shakespeare asked.
这确实是个好故事吗 莎士比亚会这样问
Is this really a good idea for a philosophical treatise?- Descartes
这确实可以作为哲学命题吗 笛卡尔
who spent a lot of time on his own reflecting.
这个花大量时间自省的人会这样问
Is this a really good idea for a philosophical treatise?
这确实可以作为哲学命题吗
Is this a good business plan? Is this the next Facebook?
这是个好的商业计划吗 这会是下一个Facebook吗
Or is this just something that I had,you know,
或者还是只是我...
the idea that I had at 3 in the morning
凌晨三点想到的
and someone has already done it or it won't work?
有人已经做过或者根本不会成功的主意
Evaluation is important.
评估非常重要
There are many idea out there- not all of them work.
世上有很多主意 但不是所有的都有用
Or to go back to our analogy of making love.
回到做爱的类比上
So you have the first stage- the foreplay.
有了第一个阶段 -前戏
You have the orgasm and afterwards,
有了高潮 然后之后
here's the question that you may be asking when you evaluate it.
就有了评估时要问的问题
Song: Will You Still Love Me Tomorrow (Sung by The Shirelles):
歌曲《你明天还会爱我吗》 The Shirelles合唱团
Is this a lasting treasure
这是持久的财富吗
Or just a moment of pleasure
还是只是短暂的愉悦
Can I believe the magic of your eyes
我能相信你眼神的魔力吗
Will you still love me tomorrow
你明天还会爱我吗
So tell me now,and I won't ask again,darling
现在就告诉我 我不会再问 亲爱的
Will you still love me tomorrow
你明天还会爱我吗
Dr.Tal Ben-Shahar:So do you know who they are? Not the parents.
你知道她们是谁吗 不是问家长们的
The students,do you recognize them? The Shirelles.
同学们 你们认得出她们吗 The Shirelles
The Shirelles.Actually my favorite group.Really.
The Shirelles合唱团 我最喜欢的组合 真的
My daughter's name,some of you know,is Shirelle.
我女儿的名字 你们有些人知道 就叫Shirelles
And we were looking for a name that
我们想起一个
would make sense in Hebrew as well as in English.
既在希伯来语里有 也在英语里有的名字
And my wife came up with the name Shirelle,
我妻子就想到了Shirelle
which means in Hebrew "song of God"
希伯来语的意思是"上帝之歌"
and you have the The Shirelles.
还有个The Shirelle合唱团
So it was just,when we found out,
所以我们发现这是
that was just the perfect name.
这是最合适的名字了
You know what I love so much about it?
你们知道我为什么这么喜欢她们吗
You can see the navy tame the dance.
你们可以看到那个范儿 舞蹈的姿势
I love that era! Just love it! Just love it.
我喜欢那个时代 非常喜欢
Anyway,go in YouTube and sign and do the Shirelles,
总之 登录youtube 搜索The Shirelles
you'll see other songs by them.So this is when you evaluate.
你们就能看到她们的其他歌了 这就是评估
We are almost done.This is when you evaluate it.
马上就讲完了 这就是评估的时候
Is this something that will last?
这会是持久的吗
Is this something that is real?
是真实的吗
A really good idea? A really good relationship? For example.
绝妙的主意? 完美的关系? 比方说
After that,
在那之后
and this doesn't have a parallel to love-making- You elaborate.
这倒是没法和做爱类比 你得详细阐明
You elaborate on the ideas.
详细阐明那些主意
So you write out,you write out the symphony.
你要写出来 把交响曲写出来
This is when you write out the treatise.
你这时要把那个命题写出来
This is when you make the business plan.
你这时要制订出来商业计划
When I put together this course,I went through this process.
我教这堂课 就经历了这整个过程
so I started off by preparing.
从准备开始
So even though I had very good preparation before,
即便我之前做了充足的准备
you know I studied for the generals twice,
我学过两遍基本知识
teaching with Professor Philip Stone as...
和Philip Stone教授一起教学
I was his TA,twice.TF.
我是他的助教 两次 助教
Even though I studied social psychology for many years and...
即便我学了很多年社会心理学...
I took time off,
我会抽出点时间
where I immersed myself in positive psychology material.
将我自己沉浸于积极心理学的材料中
I read the handbook of positive psychology
我读了积极心理学手册
which is a very good weapon to use.
这是个非常好的武器
If anyone comes close,you can just throw at them.
如果有人接近 你可以用这个砸他
It's about this big.But very good.
大概有这么厚 但是是很不错的书
I read hundreds of academic journal articles.
我读了成百上千的学术文献
And then I took time off.
然后我就抽出点时间
And during that time off,I talked about positive psychology,
在那段时间 我谈论积极心理学
but I didn't work in positive psychology.
但我不对此下太多功夫
I had conversation with my wife,with Phil Stone,
我和我妻子聊 和Phil Stone聊
with my brother about this.
和我哥哥聊
And that's when the eurekas came.That's when the insights came.
正是这时灵光一现 正是这时我顿悟了
I said,"OK so this is how the course is going to be built.
我说"这门课就应该是这样组织的
This is the spiral." Then I had the idea of PPEO,
这就是那根螺旋" 然后我想到了PPEO
Post Peak Experience Order,as an idea,an ah ha moment.
"峰值后体验" 这样的灵光一现
And afterwards,I evaluated it.I evaluated myself.
之后我就对其进行评估 我评估自身
I evaluated by talking to other people about it to see
我通过和他人交流来评估 看看
if it works and then I sat down
它是不是真的有用 然后我坐下来
and spent hours and hours and hours,writing out the lectures.
花很多很多的时间把课的内容写出来
All my lectures are written out.Obviously I don't read them.
每堂课都写了出来 显然我没有照本宣科
But in preparation,
但在准备时
when I prepare for the lectures,I do read them a few times.
在我准备上课时 我确实会看几遍
That was the elaboration.
那就是详细阐明
That is the creative process,
这就是创造的过程
whether it's putting together a class,
不管是准备一门课
or putting together a great organization,
或者运作一个机构
of writing a great book or creating a great relationship.
写本好书 或者发展一段良好的关系
I'll see you next week.Have a wonderful weekend.
下周见 周末愉快